Guide to the John Glines Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Theatrical Productions, Circa 1949-2002; Series III
  The series is comprised of manuscripts, typed scripts, notes, promotional material, reviews, playbills, programs, photographs, correspondence, contracts, and audiovisual recordings. The most substantive portion of the material documents Glines's involvement in theatrical productions (as actor, playwright, and producer) from his high school years through adulthood. To a lesser extent the material documents Glines's involvement with children's television including his work on Captain Kangaroo and Sesame Street.
  - General, The Glines, 1986, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Contracts and royalties, 1949-2002 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - "Ballet Hispanico", Circa 1973 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - "The Birds" (by Aristophanes), adapted by Walter Kerr, 1952 May (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Audiorecording [commercially produced], 1952 May; 2 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      - Use copies, 2 (Box 9.1U–9.2U)
  - "A Bitch in Amber", 1974 August (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - "Boo Hoo! East Lynne", 1959 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - "Boy on a Lonely Journey", 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Audiorecording, 1975; 1 (Box 10)
  - "Boy on a Lonely Journey", Circa 1972-1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - "Butterflies and Tigers", 1997 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - "Caine Mutiny Court Martial", 1956 May (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Captain Kangaroo, 1966-1971, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Catain Kangaroo Opera "Old Mother Bisquits" [commercially produced], Undated; 1 (Box 11)
  - "Carla's Song", 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - "A Celebration of the Life of Richard Glatfelter", Undated; 1 (Box 12)
  - "Collages" by Michael Harwood (Exhibit at The Glines), 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Comedy Theatre, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - "Dinosaurs," 3-2-1 Contact, and "There Was a Man" [commercially produced], 1978 January; 1 (Box 13)
  - "Election Songs" and "News #2", Undated; 1 (Box 14)
  - "An Evening for Quentin Crisp", 1998 June-July (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - "An Evening with Quentin Crisp", 2000 March (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "Fickle Fingers", 1994 October (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fierstein, Harvey, 1984, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Ghost Train" [commercially produced], Circa 1952-1955; 1 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 9.3U)
  - "God Bless Coney", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "The Great American Bike Show", 1975 April-June (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Gulp!", 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Music (audiorecording), Circa 1977; 1 (Box 15)
  - "Hero of My Own Life" [commercially produced], 1986 May; 1 (Box 16)
  - Historical Institute of American Music, 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "History of Mankind", 1957; 2 (Box 17)
  - "How Now, Voyager", 1997 August (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "In the Desert of My Soul", 1975, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Intimate Portrait Estelle Getty" [commercially produced], Undated; 1 (Box 18)
  - Lane, Lawrence, biofile, 1977-1979 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - "Larry Lane and Casey Wayne at Danny's", 1979 March; 1 (Box 19)
  - "The Little Hut" by Andre Roussin, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Man on the Bridge", 1963 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Misalliance" (by George Bernard Shaw), 1956 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - "Mr. Montage", Undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - "On Stage!" [commercially produced], 1950; 1 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 9.4U)
  - "On Stage!, Kay Karry reviews" [commercially produced], 1950; 1 (Box 20)
  - "On Tina Tuna Walk", Circa 1988 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - "Our Town" (by Thornton Wilder), Circa 1951 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "Murder in Disguise", 1992 June (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - "The Peanut Growers of Alabama and Georgia", 1966 December (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "Pierre Patelin" (French farce) adaptation, 1958 February (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "The Play's the Thing" (by Ferenc Molnar), 1956 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "Presenting Karen Akers" [commercially produced], 1981; 1 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Rodale Theater, New York City, 1963-1964 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "Sam and Me", 1960 November (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "So Nice to Be Here With You," "The Little Star," and "JG Special Material for Bob [McGrath]", 1979; 1 (Box 21)
  - "So What!", 1955 April (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Music (audiorecording), 1955 May; 1 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - The Saybrook Players musical revues, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - "Six Characters in Search of an Author" (by Luigi Pirandello), 1952 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - "Stamp Out AIDS at City Hall and Broadway Cares/GCN footage", Undated; 1 (Box 22)
  - "Stones of Jehoshaphat", 1963 December (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - "Stover at Yale" [commercially produced], 1954; 1 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - "Streets of Confusion", 1963 July (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Tartuffe", 1952 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - "The Tempest", 1954 February (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "The Tempest" [commercially produced], Undated; 1 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Use copy, 1 (Box 9.8U)
  - "Too True to be Good" (by George Bernard Shaw), Circa 1955 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Torch Song Trilogy", 1981 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - The Uniquecorn/"Chez Nous", 1961 Oct, December (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - "Whoop-Dee-Doo!", 1993 June (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - "The Yale Animal" [commercially produced], 1953; 4 (Box 9, Folder 9-12)
  - Yale Dramat, 1954-1955 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Untitled fragments, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Personal Papers, Circa 1800-2004; Series IV
  The series is comprised of vital records, a family genealogy, photographs and audiovisual material, and memorabilia including yearbooks, scrapbooks, and awards primarily documenting Glines's personal life. His high school and college years are particularly well documented.
  - Biographical
    - Glines family genealogy, 1994-1997 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1946-1999 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Passport, 1995-2005 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Report cards, 1941-1955 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Résumés, Circa 1960, 1980, circa 1985 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Vital and other records, 1955, 1995 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Yale, diploma, 1955 June (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Yale, The Freshman Year, 1951-1952 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - Financial
    - Women's Interart Center, Inc. loan, 1982-1984 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Stock certificates, 1967-1985 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Wills, Owen, Ellen Lanza (mother); van Waveren, Ann (friend), 1974-1986 (Box 23, Folder 10)
  - Memorabilia
    - Autograph book, 1944 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Awards
      - American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers, 1965 July (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - The Empire State Pride Agenda, 1993 September (Box 23, Folder 13)
      - Gay Academic Union, Inc., 1982 (Box 23, Folder 14)
      - Greater Westchester Human Rights Fund, 1987 June (Box 23, Folder 15)
      - President of Brooklyn citation, 2000 June (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Villager Theatre, 1981 June (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Baby book, 1933-1937 (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Certificates
      - Bangkok (Blue Elephant Cooking School), 2004 January (Box 23, Folder 18)
      - Great Wall, China, 1994 May (Box 23, Folder 19)
      - Men of Achievement, 1986 March (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Clitso, Paul (foster child), yearbooks, 1974-1975 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Drawings and paintings, 1939, 1961-1972, undated (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Honors, Emmy nominations, 1981 Jan, November (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - "Murder a la Carte Guest List", Circa 1980s (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - News clipping from Back Stage ("Keeping It Gay: A Look at America's Lesbian and Gay Theatre Companies--Then and Now"), 2001 June (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Piedmont High School
      - General, 1945-1951 (Box 24, Folder 6)
      - Cheerleading "P", Circa 1945-1951 (Box 24, Folder 7)
      - Scrapbook, 1945-1951 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Scrapbook, loose material, 1945-1951 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Yearbooks, 1946-1949 (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
      - Yearbooks, 1950-1951 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Seligman, Paul, sketches, 1960 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - "Time to Rise" (program, Straw Hat Theatre), Undated (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - "With Mary Sillers on the Grand Tour in a Simca", 1953 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - "Uncle Bill's autographed letters and newspapers", 1800-1984, undated (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Yale scrapbook, 1952-1955 (Box 27, Folder 1-3)
    - Miscellaneous, 1953-1994 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Photographs and Audiovisual Material
    - Camp Pathfinder, Circa 1930s (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Europe
      - General, 1953 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Photo album, dedicated to Mary Sillers, 1953 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Family, 1945-1993, undated (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Friends, 1948-1998, undated (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Glines, John
      - "Don's Tribute to My 40 Years", Undated; 1 (Box 28)
        Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
      - Portraits, Circa 1951-2000 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - "The Last Laugh" and "Family Loaf" (home movies?), 1942, 1950; 1 (Box 29)
    - Lorraine/Laurie (high school girlfriend), Circa 1950-1952 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Lee, Richard, 1977 November (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Moving Day, 28 Willow Street (Brooklyn Heights, NY), 1969 June (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Photo album including birthday greeting cards, playbill, comic strips, Circa 1936-1941 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Piedmont High School, Circa 1951 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Reichenau, Joe, Undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Skipper, Richard (as Carol Channing), Undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Travel
      - Amsterdam (with Gary Guo), 1999 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Chiang Mai, Thailand, 1999 March (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - China and Tibet, 1994 May-June (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - China, 1996 November (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - China, Beijing, 1998 October-November (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - China, 1999 October (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Japan, 2000 April (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Rome, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - "A Tree Grows on 57th Street", Circa 1955-1965 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Yale, Circa 1951-1955 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Yale, freshman year, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Unidentified, Circa 1960-1965 (Box 26, Folder 17)
- Additional Material, 1956-2003; Accession 2012-M-009
  This accession comprises journals of John Glines in bound and unbound formats. Correspondence and newspaper clippings my be interspersed in some journals.
  Arrangement
  Journals are arranged in chronological order.
  - Journals
    - 1956 Dec (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1958 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1961 Jan 2-Apr 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1961 Oct 10-Dec 9, 1962 Apr 24-Aug 29 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1962 Oct 11-1963 Jun 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1963 May (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1963 Jun 27-Dec 14, 1964 Feb (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1964 May 24-Dec 1, 1965 Aug 8-1966 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1966 May 1-1967 May 17 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - 1967 May 25-1968 Mar 18 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - 1968 Mar 19-1970 Jan 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - 1970 Jan 9-1971 Jul 13 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - 1971 Aug 4-1972 Aug 30 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - 1972 Aug 31-1974 Mar 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - 1974 Mar 2-1975 Mar 2, 1977 Feb-Oct (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - 1978 Mar- 1980 Jan 17-Aug 15 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - 1981 Journal entries/appointment calendar (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - 1981 Dec 14-1982, 1983-1985 Jul, 1986 Dec-1993 Mar (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - 1993 May-1995 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - 2000-2003 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Additional Material, 1991-2011; Accession 2013-M-010
  Materials in this accession consist primarily of John Glines's journal, dated 2004 to 2011. Also included are correspondence and memorabilia.
  - Journal, 2004-2011 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - "Tour to Bangkok Gay Pride," a guide to Bangkok's first gay pride festival, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bob Taylor correspondence; theater program, 2005-2006, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Additional material, 1899-1989; Accession 2017-M-025
  This accession mainly comprises scripts and accompanying sheet music for acts performed at nightclubs. There is also a small amount of personal materials such as correspondence, photographs, and drawings.
  Materials are arranged alphabetically.
  - General, 1899-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Contains correspondence, photographs, drawings, programs from performances, and historical items of interest to Glines.
  - Nightclub acts
    - Draft and final scripts and lyrics, Circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sheet music, Circa 1950s-circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Additional material, Circa 1900s-2017; Accession 2019-M-0033
  The papers are open for research. Original audiovisual materials and born digital files, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy of non-commercially produced items for their personal use should consult the ordering reproductions information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
  The materials are arranged into four groupings: I. Correspondence. II. Writings. III. Theatrical productions. IV. Personal papers.
  The accession consists of the writings of playwright John Glines, including scripts of productions performed at The Glines Theatre in New York City, personal and autobiographical writings, and a daily journal. The papers also include correspondence and recordings of author Erlo Van Waveren and production materials from Glines's play Butterflies and Tigers, including video and audio recordings.
  - Correspondence
    - Van Waveren, Erlo, 1967-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Writings
    - Journal, 1933-2017 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
    - Personal and autobiographical writings, Circa 1960s-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5-9)
  - Theatrical productions
    - Butterflies and Tigers
      - Butterflies and Tigers, Circa 1998; 1 (Box 3)
        Original born digital files, as well as preservation masters, may not be accessed due to their fragility. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist request that they be made. Born digital files cannot be accessed remotely. System requirements include a Manuscripts and Archives computer and file viewing software.
      - Butterflies and Tigers interview, 1998; 1 (Box 4)
      - Butterflies and Tigers production material, 1996-1998 (Box 1, Folder 10-12)
      - Butterflies and Tigers script, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Butterflies and Tigers script, Orenda Theatre, Circa 1998; 1 (Box 5)
      - Butterflies and Tigers, Trilogy Theatre, Circa 1998; 1 (Box 6)
    - The Glines productions by John Glines and others, 1976-1999 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      Includes "A Production History of The Glines" with list of theatrical productions
    - Gulp!
      - Gulp!, 1978; 1 (Box 7)
      - Gulp! music, 2nd cast, 1976; 1 (Box 8)
      - Gulp! script, 1977-1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Personal papers
    - "Dedicated to the Myth", transcript of talk by Erlo Van Waveren, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Erlo, 1-2 of 3, 1983-11; 1 (Box 9)
    - Erlo, 3 of 3, 1983-11; 1 (Box 10)
    - Erlo talk, side 1 and 2, 1983-11-01; 1 (Box 11)
    - Erlo talk, side 3 and 4, 1983-11-01; 1 (Box 12)
    - Erlo talk, side 1 and 2 copy, 1983-11-01; 1 (Box 13)
    - Erlo talk, side 3 and 4 copy, 1983-11-01; 1 (Box 14)
    - Mao speech, no dolby, Circa 1990s; 1 (Box 15)
    - Mao speech, old, with applause, Circa 1990s; 1 (Box 16)
    - Personal and family memorabilia, 1950-2014 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Personal and family photographs, Circa 1900s-1970s (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Photographs from album, Circa 1970s (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Profile, The Gay and Lesbian Review, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Songs with lyrics of Mao Zedong's poems, Circa 1990s; 1 (Box 17)